There are around 600,000 vegans in the UK, according to The Vegan Society. That's just over 1% of the population – an amount expected to increase to 25% by 2025.
据英国素食协会统计，英国目前约有60万素食主义者，仅占总人口的1%多一点——不过这一比例预计到2025年将增至25%。
And if there's one type of food that Brits love, it's fast food.
而英国人最爱的食物之一，无疑是快餐。
True, it's not the most nutritious, but there's nothing quite like the crunch of crispy chips, or that first big bite into a juicy hamburger.
诚然，快餐并非最有营养的选择，但酥脆薯条的咔嚓声，或是第一口咬下多汁汉堡的满足感，都是无可替代的。
People in the UK love junk food so much that there was a 34% increase in the number of fast food outlets from 2010 to 2018, according to the Office for National Statistics.
英国国家统计局的数据显示，2010年至2018年间，英国快餐门店数量增长了34%，由此可见英国人对垃圾食品的热爱。
It's no surprise, then, that vegan fast food is also on the rise.
因此，素食快餐的兴起也不足为奇。
Vegan fast food has become big business.
素食快餐已成为一门大生意。
At Just Eat, an online food delivery company, vegan orders more than doubled in 2018, a spokesperson told the BBC.
在线外卖平台Just Eat的发言人向英国广播公司表示，2018年该平台的素食订单量增长了一倍多。
Greggs, a chain of high-street bakeries, named its vegan sausage roll the 'fastest-selling product in six years'.
繁华商业街连锁烘焙品牌格雷格斯（Greggs）将其推出的素食香肠卷称为“六年来最畅销产品”。
And big franchises such as McDonald's and KFC have announced meat-free chicken nuggets to come in the future.
麦当劳、肯德基等大型连锁品牌也已宣布，未来将推出无肉鸡块。
What's driving this popularity?
是什么催生了素食快餐的流行？
Katrina Fox, founder of Vegan Business Media, believes it's the result of social media and the breaking down of stereotypes.
素食商业媒体（Vegan Business Media）创始人卡特里娜·福克斯认为，这得益于社交媒体的推动以及刻板印象的打破。
"Vegan food is no longer seen as a bit of lettuce and lentils – you can eat pretty much anything," she told the BBC.
她向英国广播公司表示：“素食不再被看作只有生菜和小扁豆——你几乎可以吃到任何想吃的东西。”
It's also claimed that there are health benefits.
还有人称，素食快餐对健康有益。
John Marulanda, owner of Mooshies - a vegan burger bar in London – wants to implement "a change to a healthy version of fast food." Something, he claims, that comes as a result of the inherent nutritional value of the ingredients they use.
伦敦素食汉堡店Mooshies的老板约翰·马鲁兰达希望“推动快餐向健康化转型”，他表示，这得益于他们所使用食材本身的营养价值。
But, is vegan fast food actually healthy?
但素食快餐真的健康吗？
Azmina Govindji of the British Dietetic Association says "not to assume" that is the case.
英国饮食协会的阿兹米娜·戈文德吉表示，“不能想当然地”认为事实就是如此。
"It's fine if those products have got vitamin B12, iodine or calcium added to them… but they can still be fried, it can still have lots of creamy, fatty sauces and lots of salt."
“如果这些产品添加了维生素B12、碘或钙，那当然是好事……但它们仍可能经过油炸，可能含有大量奶油状高脂酱料，且含盐量不低。”
Given the current growth in orders, the trend for vegan fast food isn't likely to disappear any time soon.
从目前订单的增长趋势来看，素食快餐的热潮短期内不太可能消退。
Health-wise, it may not be any more nourishing than regular fast food, but for many, the lack of animal suffering involved in the process is a big plus.
就健康而言，它或许并不比普通快餐更具营养价值，但对许多人来说，生产过程中不涉及动物受苦，这便是一大优势。